2-spyware.com 2019-06-14

# Privacy Information Notice

**Next Review Date:** 21st June 2020

At Elektroniniai sprendimai, we’re committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This Policy explains when and why we collect personal information, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and what choices you have.

We may change this Policy from time to time so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes. By using our services, you’re agreeing to be bound by this Policy.

Any questions regarding this Policy and our privacy practices should be filled via the questions form on our contact page.

## Summary

Who are we? – We are Elektroniniai sprendimai, a company dedicated to help users learn more about computers and cybersecurity.

How do we collect information from you? – We obtain information about you when you contact us to enquire about our services and when you use our website.

What information do we collect & how is it used? – We collect information to allow us to fulfil our obligations to our clients, and to respond to business enquiries. We also collect your information if you submit questions on our website or leave blog comments.

Controlling your information – You have certain rights concerning the information we hold about you, as defined under the General Data Protection Regulation. If you wish to exercise these rights, please contact us.

Use of ‘cookies’ – This website uses cookies; by using and browsing the Elektroniniai sprendimai website, you consent to cookies being used in accordance with this Policy. If you do not consent, you must turn off cookies or refrain from using the site.

Security – Elektroniniai sprendimai takes security seriously. Our internal Data Security Policy details the steps we take to safeguard and secure the information we collect.

Data Breaches – Our Data Security Policy includes a clear process for handling a personal data breach, should one occur. Where appropriate, Elektroniniai sprendimai will promptly notify you of any unauthorized access to your personal information.

Complaints – If you wish to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal information, you can contact us directly and we will investigate the matter.

## 1\. Who are we?

We are Elektroniniai sprendimai, a company dedicated to help users learn more about computers, related issues and security. Our registered address is I. Kanto street 18-1, Kaunas, LT44296, LITHUANIA. Full contact details can be found [here](https://www.2-spyware.com/contact-us).

## 2\. How do we collect information from you?

We obtain information about you when you contact us to enquire about our services. We also collect information from you if you submit a question on our website or leave blog comments.

## 3\. What information do we collect & how is it used?

We collect information to allow us to fulfil our obligations to our clients, and to respond to business enquiries. We also collect your information if you submit a question on our site. The table in section 3.3 below outlines exactly what information we collect, and for what purpose.

#### 3.0. Sensitive Data

We do not gather sensitive personal data (e.g. health, genetic, biometric data; racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, sexual orientation, and criminal convictions). We expressly request that you do not provide any such sensitive data to us.

#### 3.1. Children’s information

Our services are not directed to children under 13. If you learn that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information without consent, please contact us.

#### 3.2. Third Parties

We will not sell or rent your information to third-parties. We will not share your information with third-parties for marketing purposes.

We may pass your information to third-party service providers who we have engaged for the purpose of completing tasks and providing services to you on our behalf. We disclose only the personal information that is necessary to deliver the service.

We also show advertisements and third-party content, which might also use ‘cookies’ for providing the best services to our visitors. This includes the following third-parties for displaying advertisements through networks, but is not limited to:

  * AddThis;
  * Google Adsense/DFP.

Affiliate networks to attribute software downloads:

  * Cleverbridge.com
  * Cj.com
  * Avangate.com
  * Revenuewire.com

Elektroniniai sprendimai is not responsible for the information which is collected by third-parties. If you want to avoid this, you can reject their cookies or ask to delete your data.

We also use a number of 3rd party services to help us fulfill our contractual obligations – for example, we use Cloudflare which provides web optimization and security services to improve our website.

These 3rd party services are listed in full below; we have verified that these 3rd party services are GDPR compliant (or are working towards GDPR compliance), and are certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework (or are working towards certification) where these organisations are based outside of the EU.

#### 3.3. Details

The following table outlines the personal data we collect and for what purpose. The table also outlines the 3rd parties the data is processed by or shared with, and how long the data is stored for:

Name

| 

What

| 

Legal Ground

| 

Purpose

| 

Third-parties

| 

Data Retention  
  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
  
Email

| 

Email address

| 

Contract

| 

Can be collected once the user wants to contact us without registering with Twitter, Facebook or Google+

| 

SendGrid

| 

Until a request for deletion is received  
  
Blog  Comments

| 

Website commenter name, email address and website (Unless you register with Twitter, Facebook or Google+)

| 

Contract

| 

To allow website users to comment on and discuss blog posts, or ask questions

| 

Held within WordPress database, hosted with Disqus

| 

Until a request for deletion is received  
  
Password Store

| 

Client log-in details for submitting questions and blog comments

| 

Legitimate interests

| 

To allow us to log in and administer services on our clients’ behalf

| 

–

| 

Until a request for deletion is received  
  
Backup

| 

Backup of documents on local drives

| 

Legitimate interests

| 

Cloud backup to ensure business continuity in the event of hardware failure

| 

–

| 

Until a request for deletion is received  
  
Analytics

| 

Website visitor behaviour (anonymised – full IP address is NOT stored)

| 

Legitimate interests

| 

To analyse popular content, website performance, etc – so we can further improve

| 

Google Analytics

| 

Stored indefinitely  
  
Server Logs

| 

IP address

| 

Legal obligation

| 

To help prevent DoS (Denial of Service) attacks; for website security and diagnostics

| 

–

| 

Server logs are first stored unencrypted and then moved to an encrypted backup which is stored indefinitely  
  
DNS Log Data

| 

IP address, system configuration information, etc.

| 

Legitimate interests

| 

Cloudflare provides DNS, web optimization and security services for our website

| 

Cloudflare

| 

Stored indefinitely  
  
## 4\. Controlling your information

You have certain rights concerning the information we hold about you, as defined under the General Data Protection Regulation. If you wish to exercise these rights, please contact us, including your email and IP addresses in the first instance (this is the unique identifiers we use to identify and collate personal information).

### 4.0. Requesting a copy of your information

You may request a copy of any data we hold about you. Upon request, we will provide a CSV file containing the personal data we hold on record about you.

### 4.1. Updating or correcting your information

The accuracy of your information is important to us. If you change email address, or any of the other information we hold is inaccurate or out of date, please contact us so we may correct our records.

### 4.2. Deleting your information

You have the right to request the erasure of your personal information. Unless there is a compelling reason for the data not to be erased (for example, if we need to use that data to fulfill our contractual or legal obligations), your personal data will be deleted on request.

Users have the ability to leave comments on our blog. To maintain the flow of conversation, blog comments will not normally be deleted (unless there is a compelling reason to do so), but all personally identifying information will be removed.

### 4.3. Automated decision making

We do not use any personal information for automated decision making or profiling; your data is not subject to automated decision making or profiling.

## 5\. Use of “cookies”

Like many other websites, the 2-spyware.com website uses cookies. Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website.

The cookies we use are ‘1st party’ cookies.  We don’t use any ’3rd party’ cookies (these are often used to track behaviour across a range of websites, so targeted advertising can then be applied. We don’t do this!) The following list outlines what we use cookies for:

**Google Analytics:**   
Google Analytics sets cookies to help us accurately estimate the number of visitors to the website and what content is most popular. This helps to ensure that our website is responding to your needs in the best way possible.

**Disqus:**  
Disqus app allows our users to submit blog comments and discuss about the latest cyber threats. Note that they might have a different Privacy Policy which applies to their services. Elektroniniai sprendimai is not responsible for the information it collects and its ‘cookies.’

By using and browsing the 2-spyware.com website, you consent to cookies being used in accordance with this Policy.

If you do not consent, you must turn off cookies or refrain from using the site. Most browsers allow you to turn off cookies. To do this, look at the ‘help’ menu on your browser. Switching off cookies should not noticeably restrict your use of this website.

## 6\. Security

Elektroniniai sprendimai takes security seriously. In order to protect your information from loss, misuse or unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect. These steps include the following:

  * Data minimisation;
  * Password best practice;
  * Security best practice concerning devices (PCs, laptops, mobile devices), online accounts, website hosting, physical access, and storage;
  * Staff training and accountability on data protection;

## 7\. Data Breaches

Our Data Security Policy includes a clear process for handling a personal data breach, should one occur. Where appropriate, Elektroniniai sprendimai will promptly notify you of any unauthorized access to your personal information.

## 8\. Complaints

If you wish to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal information, you can contact us directly via [info@esolutions.lt](mailto:info@esolutions.lt) and we will investigate the matter.

If you are not satisfied with our response or believe we are processing your personal information not in accordance with the law you can complain to the [State Data Protection Inspectorate](https://www.ada.lt/).
